安东尼・福奎亚作品
主演：马克・沃尔伯格
《生死狙击》
迈克尔・佩纳
丹尼・格洛沃
凯特・玛拉
埃利亚斯・考蒂斯
罗纳・迈特拉
拉德・舍博德加
莱沃恩・赫尔姆
尼德・巴蒂
泰特・多诺万　贾斯汀・路易斯
浅蓝色字体为本片中出现枪械的注解
M40A3
是在雷明登700的基础上开发的军用狙击步枪
有动静
Movement.
有两人
Two men.
与M40A1的外观区别是可调高低的枪托
大约还有…
Approximately
枪瞄：Unertl 10X 瞄准镜
四十只羊
40 goats.
它们不是敌人，没必要射杀
They're not on anybody's side. We don't have to shoot them.
撤退方向？
Egress?
首选空中撤离，其次是公路 再次是水路
Primary over the top, secondary down the road, tertiary to the river.
在河里没人能追踪你 除了鱼儿
No one can track you through the water except a fish.
莎拉下个月就进护士学校
Sarah's headed off to nursing school next month.
她自己努力的成果
She sewed that herself.
她很漂亮
It's beautiful.
你肯定这是个维和任务吗？
You sure this is a peacekeeping mission?
通常不会一开始就这么和平
Normally there isn't any peace to start with.
现在周围寂静得吓人
This shit's awful calm.
伯朗宁M2HB式12.7mm大口径机枪
于1933年定型，从二战到现在约有50多个国家使用
埃塞俄比亚 美军雷门尼尔营地 海军基地之一，是美国在非洲之角的重要战略基地
不是这个坐标 是，长官
- Not at these coordinates. - Yes, sir.
继续制订后备计划
Go ahead and plot an alternate.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
指挥所，这里是 TS-129，完毕
Command Post, Command Post, this is TS-129, over.
长官，我已经观察到 TS-129 当前位置
Sir, I have visual confirmation of TS-129's current position.
任务完成，正前往撤离点 还有八公里
Mission accomplished, en route to extract site. Distance eight klicks. Over.
指挥所，毒蛇呼叫
Command Post, Command Post, this is Viper.
发现友军正往撤离点行动
I have friendly forces moving towards extraction point, over.
注意了，我们的人正在过来
Heads up, our boys are coming through.
毒蛇注意，这里是指挥所
Viper, this is CP. Be advised,
有可疑武装分子 从正面向 TS-129 进攻
possible hostile forces approaching TS-129 at their 12:00.
结束对话
Call them out.
目标
Target.
B 区纵深地带
Sector Bravo, deep.
伯朗宁M2HB式12.7mm大口径机枪
Vehicle, belt-fed weapon.
卡车一辆，载有重机枪
距离？
Range it.
距离八百七十码，正在接近
870 yards and closing.
风向，偏右 3/4，修正 2 分
Wind, three-quarter value, push 2 left.
公路九百码处有一开阔地带
900 yards. Wide spot on the road.
目标锁定
On target.
随时待命
Hold scope.
可以射击了
Fire when ready.
命中
Hit.
指挥所，毒蛇呼叫 威胁已解除，完毕
Command Post, this is Viper. Hostile threat down, over.
毒蛇，这里是指挥所 收到报告，完毕
Viper, this is Command Post. We copy your traffic, over.
告诉他们，我们可以撤了
Call it in. It's time to go.
指挥所，毒蛇呼叫 任务完成
Command Post, this is Viper. Mission accomplished.
准备撤离 见鬼！
- Packing up. - Shit!
毒蛇请注意，大批 武装分子正在 B 区接近你
Viper, be advised larger hostile forces approaching near sector Bravo.
怎么让敌人靠得这么近
Weren't supposed to be hostiles that close!
俄罗斯DShK/DShKM 12.7mm重机枪
全称捷格加廖夫-斯帕金大口径机枪
古奇树，六百七十五码 时速三十英里，提前量三密耳
Crooked tree. 675, 30 miles an hour, three-mil lead.
1938年定型，简称德什卡重机枪
那个机枪射手，九百码，偏右 3/4
Position to machine gun. 900, three-quarter value.
好了就打
Fire when ready.
敌方头目，九百二十码，偏右 3/4
Jefe. 920. Three-quarter value.
我见到了， 唐尼 可以打了
- I see it, Donnie. I see it. - Fire when ready.
他们不知道我们位置 但最怕误打误中
- They don't know where we are. - But they might get lucky!
指挥所，毒蛇呼叫
Command Post, Command Post, this is Viper.
我们已将敌人拦截
Enemy forces have been stopped. Break.
我方人员继续向撤离地点前进
Friendlies are continuing on to extract point. Break.
我们受到敌方小型 武器和迫击炮攻击
We're receiving small arms and indirect fire from hostile troops. Break.
指挥所，听到没有？
Command Post, do you read me?
关闭仪器
Shut it down.
他们两个训练有素
They're highly-trained men,
在那一地区作战违反国际法
eight kilometers inside a country we are not supposed to be in.
他们自己完全有能力撤退 停止一切联络
I'm sure they'll get out just fine. Shut it down now.
检查通讯，有没有收到？
Radio check. Do you read me?
收拾东西，我们走 有没有收到？
- Okay, wrap it up. Let's go! - Do you read me?
把录音拿出来 把录音拿出来收拾好
- Pull out those tracks. - Pull out those tracks and pack it up!
SOPMOD M4
M4系列是最能代表美国的卡宾枪
SOPMOD是1992年在M4A1基础上
提出的特种作战改进型
用模块化来方便安装附件
情报说他们没有空中支援啊
Intelligence said they didn't have air support!
马上报告
Call it in!
见鬼！频段关闭了
Shit! The channel's down!
不可能
That's impossible!
通讯失效了
The comm link's dead!
我们被放弃了 没关系，我们自己会回去
They left us here. Don't worry, we're getting home!
M2内红点瞄具、M203枪挂式榴弹发射器
M203是美军70年代定型的榴弹发射器
标准的M203通常安装在M16或M4枪管下
可发射高爆弹、烟雾弹、照明弹、CS毒气弹等…
M2内红点瞄具是瑞典Aimpoint公司的
Comp M系列快速瞄准镜
无放大倍数
唐尼？
Donnie?
唐尼！
Donnie!
巴雷特M82A3 点50口径反器材步枪
巴雷特公司M82系列是当今使用最广泛的
大口径狙击步枪之一
A3是在A1的基础上的改进型陆战队型号
陆军型号为M82A1M
外观特征与M82A1的区别是原镜桥位置改成了…
一条延伸至枪身前端的M1913皮卡汀尼导轨
三十六个月后
过来，小子
Come on, boy!
过来，山姆！
Come on, Sam!
干什么？
What're you doing, huh? What're you doing?
过来
Come on.
我没吃的了
What? I got nothing.
干什么？
What?
我们走，走吧
All right, come on, let's go. Let's go.
好孩子，进去
That's a good boy.
好孩子
Good boy.
看看他们又会推销些 什么骗人东西
Well, let's see what lies they're trying to sell us today.
过来
Here, boy.
好孩子
Good boy.
弗吉尼亚州，兰利
枪炮中士鲍勃・李・史瓦格
Gunnery Sergeant Bob Lee Swagger.
海军陆战队退役队员
USMC, retired.
他是最佳人选
He is the best there is.
他最后一次执行任务时发生意外
His last assignment went wrong.
他成了情报机构执行任务的牺牲品
Put in unfriendly territory on a loan-out and left as expendable.
敌人出动了攻击直升机和 一个连的兵力向他们攻击
Opposing force sent an attack helicopter and a hundred-man company.
他的好友兼目标观察员阵亡
His best friend and spotter was killed.
没有正式报告
No official report.
秘密报告称，他消灭了 70％的敌人，其余逃走
Ghost report says he inflicted 70 percent casualties, the rest fled.
将他丢弃在那的情报部门长官
The agency asset that left them there to die?
两周后消失得无影无踪
Suddenly removed from the face of the earth two weeks after.
但没有人起诉鲍勃・李
They never laid it at Bob Lee's feet.
他一周以后退役
He retired a week later.
我想他自己不甘心做牺牲品
I guess Bob Lee didn't think he was expendable.
他自己种地和打猎为生？
Grows and shoots his own food.
是的，他很少离开山里
Yeah, he rarely ventures out at all.
他是一个有责任感的爱国主义者
This is a man with a history of duty and patriotism.
爱国主义是他始终如一的信仰 明白
- Not as punch lines, but as core beliefs. - Aye.
有些人一旦信仰破灭就会无所适从
Some people don't know what to do when their belief system collapses.
鲍勃・李就是那类人
Bob Lee is one of those.
你确定有人吗？
You sure, boy?
不，我不需要买任何东西
Nope. I ain't buying. I don't want any.
从哪来回哪去
You guys turn around and go back to wherever you came from.
鲍勃・李・史瓦格？
Bob Lee Swagger?
我是艾萨克・约翰逊上校
My name is Colonel Isaac Johnson.
你可够难找的
You're a hard man to find.
难度还不够
But not hard enough.
我们从很远的地方来
Come a long way to see you.
有件事想和你谈谈
We have some business needs your attention.
下山时要打一档
You wanna use your low gear going down the road
不然刹车会失灵
or your brakes'll go.
过来，乖狗 小心点
- Come here. Come here, boy. - Don't do that.
没有我的邀请你过不去 除非打死他
Come near the porch I didn't invite you, you'd have to shoot the dog.
你的速度不行
That's a slow draw you got there.
你想找死吗？
Sure you want to do that?
在这谁想杀死我的狗
Shoot a dog in this county on a man's land,
我就把他埋到山里 就算一两个月后告诉治安官
I'd bury you in the hill, and tell the sheriff a month or two later.
他也能理解
He understands.
把你的手从枪上拿开
Take your hand off your weapon.
慢慢来
Slowly.
别让枪炮中士真的把你埋在山里
So the gunnery sergeant doesn't have to bury you in the hill.
我没带枪
I don't carry a gun.
知道这是什么吗？
You know what that is?
国会荣誉勋章 美国政府颁发的最高军事荣衔
It's a Congressional Medal of Honor.
很少人能够得到它
They don't hand those out easy.
是你的？
Yours?
是的
Yeah.
你父亲也得到过，对吗？
Your father had one, didn't he?
你怎么得到的？
What did you do?
全靠玩命 我救了另一个战友的性命
Something foolhardy. Kept some other boys alive.
给我五分钟好吗？
Will you give me five minutes?
让你的走狗在外面等
Yeah, your dog stays outside.
过来，孩子，进去
Come on, boy. Get in there.
我需要你制订一个刺杀总统的计划
I need you to plan a presidential assassination.
哪国总统？
Whose president?
我国总统
Ours.
不是真的刺杀
I didn't say 'execute'.
只是计划
Plan.
为的是阻止真的计划发生
So it can be stopped.
情报部门说有人计划 在两周内刺杀总统
There's gonna be an attempt on the life of the President in the next two weeks.
我们破译了一段匿名密码
Code was broken on an anonymous transmission.
出自政府内部
It was internal.
所以不能让政府部门参与破案
We can't go to the usual agencies.
敌人已经打入内部
The government itself has been penetrated.
这段时间，总统 要参加3项公开活动
The President has three public engagements during that time.
分别在巴尔的摩、费城 和华盛顿特区
Baltimore, Philadelphia, Washington, D.C.
特勤局的标准警戒线…
Standard Secret Service protective cordon
通常设在八百八十码之外
is out to 880 yards.
但截获的情报称，这次 袭击地点会定在1英里之外
But this intercept claims that the shot will be taken from beyond a mile.
你去实地勘查一下 然后告诉我们你的做法
We need you to scout, tell us how you would do it,
我们就会阻止他
so we could stop it.
不过老实说，我不大相信 这样的袭击会得逞
I'm not entirely convinced that a shot like this could be made.
但不能掉以轻心
But let's not take the chance.
你的远距离射击能力到底怎样？
Your longer shots were never confirmed.
远距离射击通常发生在…
That's because long shots generally go places
你们不愿意去确认的场合
you wouldn't wanna have to go afterwards to confirm them.
确认只是做表面文章而已
Confirmation's a desk pogue's problem.
知道远距离射击要考虑什么吗？
You know what it takes to make a shot at that range?
需要考虑所有相关的因素：
Everything comes into play that far.
湿度、温度、高度、 风向、扬尘…
Humidity, elevation, temperature, wind, spindrift.
子弹飞向目标需要六到十秒时间
There's a 6- to10-second flight time
所以必须估算提前量
so you have to shoot at where the target's going to be.
甚至科里奥利作用*和地球自转都得考虑 *对旋转体系中进行直线运动的质点由于惯性产生偏移的一种描述
Even the Coriolis effect, the spin of the Earth, comes into play.
总统会穿防弹衣，所以要射击头部
President'll be wearing body amour. That means a headshot,
还要在一英里之外
at over a mile.
你相信真有这么大本事的枪手吗？
You believe there's a shooter involved capable of making this shot?
我相信
Yes.
那麻烦可就大了 你们一定要找到枪手
Well, then you got a real problem. You need to find the shooter.
那是另一批人的任务
That's being worked on from another direction.
我们需要你干这事
We need you to do this.
我根本不喜欢现任总统
Don't really like the President much.
前任总统更不喜欢
Didn't like the one before that much, either.
但是你喜欢总统制吗？
You like the idea of the President?
喜欢自由的国家吗？
Living in a free country?
难道我们能容忍让坏人统治吗…
Do we allow America to be ruled by thugs?
没关系，几年而已
Sure, some years we do.
我相信你曾站在国旗前…
I believe you stood before a flag
庄严宣誓过…
and solemnly swore
要支持和捍卫美国宪法…
that you'd support and defend the Constitution of the United States
抗击一切敌人
against all enemies,
无论来自国内外
foreign and domestic.
五分钟到了
I think your five minutes is up.
听着，孩子
Listen to me, son.
我不希望你下星期打开电视
I don't want you to turn on the TV next week
看到总统身亡时…
and see the President dead,
后悔自己没阻止这一切
and know you could've done something about it.
希望你好自为之
Don't do that to yourself.
这是新型号吗？
Is that the new one?
那辆车
The truck.
装有大马力发动机？
You got the big engine in there?
我看看，八升 V-8 发动机
Wow, look at that, huh? Eight-liter V8.
厉害，环保署竟然 不管你的每公里油耗
Thing's so big, EPA doesn't even bother to give you the gas mileage for it.
我能拍张照吗？
You mind if I take a picture?
真漂亮
This is beautiful.
这电话二十四小时都有人接听
Someone will be at this number night or day.
看到他刚才做什么了吗？ 他才不是在拍发动机
You see what he did? He didn't need a photo of the engine.
他醉翁之意不在酒
No, he doesn't give a rat's ass about the engine.
他受过反侦察训练
He's trained in counterintel.
他的距离足以把车牌照下来
Backed up far enough to take a picture of the plates.
我们就需要这种人
This is our guy.
他好像拒绝你了
I thought he turned you down.
他答应了，只是自己没有意识到
He said yes. He just doesn't know it yet.
Cheytac Intervention M200 点408口径
CheyTac LRRS(远射程步枪系统）系列之一
手动旋转后拉枪机
该枪标配的瞄准镜是Ningtforce的NXS5.5－22倍镜
现时的2321码射击世界记录保持枪
一英里大概一千七百六十码
1,760's a mile.
真够远，你觉得总统会有事吗？
It's a far piece, Sam. Think the President ought to worry?
看来总统凶多吉少
Yeah, I think he better worry.
它不会有事
Yeah, he'll be fine.
每天喂它一次 孤独时给它念念弹道表就没事了
Just feed him once a day. Read him a few ballistics tables if he looks lonely.
好，再见
Yep. I'm out.
老朋友
Come here, buddy.
好了
Okay.
我出几天门你不会寂寞吧？
Think you'll be able to tough it out without me for a couple days?
那好
Yeah.
华盛顿特区
马里兰州，巴尔的摩
宾夕法尼亚州，费城
这里是指挥所，你们情况如何？
This is Command Post. What's your status? Over.
我们完成了第六条街
Yeah, we're finishing up here on 6th.
收到，请随时报告情况
Roger that. We copy. Checkpoint down, over.
各位面前的是独立宫 美利坚合众国的发源地
Before you stands Independence Hall, the birthplace of the United States
是美国历史上的重要建筑之一
and one of the most important buildings in American history.
于一七三二年建成
Built in 1732...
随时留意七十二号…
Keep a visual eye on 72nd...
是独立宣言以及美国宪法的签署地
...both the Declaration of Independence and the U.S. Constitution
were debated and signed here.
三个城市中…
Out of the three cities,
只有一个最有可能实施暗杀
there's only one with a reasonably high chance of success.
巴尔的摩没有足够空间
There was no room in Baltimore.
街道狭窄，修正风受影响
Street isn't wide enough to correct for the windage,
建筑物遮挡视线
buildings are in the way.
去华盛顿特区等于自杀
D.C.'s a pure suicide mission.
I mean, unless you're sure your shooter's interested in 70 virgins
来生那70个处女* *引自哈马斯恐怖分子在招募时的话“如果你成为一位烈士，真主将会赐予你70个处女”
waiting for him in the afterlife,
否则免谈
I'd rule that out.
这次袭击只能在费城
Shot's got to be taken from Philly.
而且只能在一千八百码外进行
From beyond 1,800 yards, though.
一共有六个可能位置
It's one of six possible locations,
其中一个是位于总统上方五层楼
approximately five stories above the President's location.
估计子弹会飞行五到六秒
Flight time of the bullet that distance is five to six seconds.
他们会等到总统站到讲台开始演讲
They'll have to wait till he takes the podium,
开始讲几句之后
several lines into his speech.
那时他处于静止状态
That way he'd be completely static, obviously at his most exposed.
而且会选用大口径武器
Shot requires a large-caliber weapon.
很可能使用自制子弹 选用青铜合金
Expect the bullet to be handmade, bronzed alloy turned on a lathe.
弹道系数稍低一些
Slightly lower ballistics coefficient,
弹身更光滑
touch more slippery.
这就是我的做法
Least that's what I'd do.
那么远你能保证打死他吗？
You can kill him from that far away?
一英里半，子弹动能达到最大
Mile and a half, the bullet's going to strike with more energy
比点四四 Magnum 手枪的威力还大
than a.44 Magnum point blank.
不成问题
Yeah, I think you can kill him.
麻烦的是风向
The challenge is the wind.
距离太远，一丝微风都会坏事
Lightest breeze uncorrected at that distance
is enough to ruin the shot.
他必须在讲台位置和 射击位置之间设立指示物
He's gonna need indicators between the podium and the shooting position.
速度校正比较容易
Velocity corrections are easy,
但角度修正涉及到三角学问
but an angle change, that becomes a trig problem.
他必须一瞬间完成心算
He's gotta do that in his head on the fly.
否则想一枪命中非常困难
Without something to gauge, your shot's just too tough to make cold bore.
一份完美的报告，小子
Impressive recon and report, son.
如果下手过早，他有可能逃走
Move too soon, we lose him.
我们想抓活的
We want to take him alive.
不查出黑手，悲剧还会发生
If we don't know who hired him, it could just happen again.
我们有六个三人小组随时待命
We'll have six three-man teams standing by.
史瓦格军士？
Gunnery Sergeant Swagger?
请留步
A moment?
你为国家做了很大贡献
You've done your country a great service, son.
到时候… 不，听着…
- On the day... - Look...
听我说
Listen.
你是少数了解内情的人之一
You're one of the few people who knows what to look for.
我需要观察员
I could use a spotter.
谢谢，费城
Thank you, Philadelphia.
总统二十分钟内发表演说
The President speaks in 20 minutes.
…站在各位面前的讲台上…
...before you on this stage...
通知火力小组各就位
Notify our teams. Check their positions.
…当年爱国者们共聚 独立宫草拟了一份文件
...patriots met in Independence Hall and created a document,
创立了《独立宣言》
the Declaration of Independence...
长官
Sir?
…和创立了美利坚合众国
...and a country, the United States of America,
并改变了世界
that changed the world.
费城是我们的家园…
Philadelphia is our home. We are...
各小组注意，这里是监听站
Stand by, all teams. This is Listening Post.
闪光已进入 J 点
Flashlight's current location is approaching Checkpoint Jason.
雷明登 700PSS/DM
各狙击小组报告情况
All sniper teams send update on your sitrep.
PSS（Police Sharp Shooter）警用枪
是雷明登公司为执法机构设计的
待命 我们的视线很清楚
- Stand by. - Yes, I have a clear line of sight.
长年来在无数执法部门服役
可卸弹匣的版本为700DM
收到
Copy that.
十八号哨位，一切正常
Post 18 clear, over.
十九号哨位，请报告情况
Post 19, please report. What's your status?
一切正常，没发现什么可疑情况
All clear. There's really nothing going on here.
埃塞俄比亚大主教…
The Archbishop of Ethiopia...
总统先生稍后会颁发费城友谊奖章
The President will be awarding the Philadelphia Brotherhood Medal
给埃塞俄比亚大主教 德斯蒙德・穆托姆博
to His Grace Desmond Mutumbo, the Archbishop of Ethiopia.
这位大主教一直是位有争议的人物
There's been some controversy surrounding the Archbishop
因他常揭露发生在他的国家的暴行
as he's been speaking out regarding the atrocities in his country.
他计划在此次颁奖结束后
He plans to meet with the President right after the ceremony
与美国总统举行会谈
to discuss these matters.
这是伟大的时代
These are great times.
是具有历史意义的时代
These are historic times.
也是动荡不安的时代
And these are troubled times, as well.
贵国的这个奖章
This medal that your country...
黄丝带
Yellow ribbons.
对，那是用来向军队表达敬意的
Yeah, people put those up to remember the troops.
应该放在树下吧
No, they tie those low around trees.
这些是风向标
These are windage flags.
由此判断，大概射击位置…
Roughly the location I'd have put them in
会在教堂塔顶上
for a shot from the steeple.
是的，有可能
Yeah. Maybe.
绝对是，他是个行家里手
No, definitely. He knows what he's doing.
教堂方向安排狙击小组了吗？
You guys got a team in place to take out the church?
如果那里有人 他们会在枪响之前采取行动
They'll move right before the shot is taken, when his focus is elsewhere.
…那些对抗自由的势力渐渐抬头
...raises its head and confronts freedom,
妄图把自由扼杀在摇篮里
but slyly, subtly, chokes it off at the root.
我们的责任是…
And it is our responsibility
彻底铲除这些有害的苗头
to find these dark weeds.
闪光已经抵达，重复一遍 闪光已经抵达
Flashlight has arrived. I say again, Flashlight has arrived.
如果你刚打开电视… 你好
- If you just joined us... - Hi.
提蒙斯警官，本地分局的
Officer Timmons, our local resource.
这是鲍勃・李・史瓦格
Bob Lee Swagger.
认识你非常荣幸
It is a real honor to meet you.
你的枪套扣松开了
You're unsnapped, officer.
我靠…
Shit. Oh, fuck.
GLOCK系列手枪
丢了枪可麻烦了
Don't want to lose that now, do I?
奥地利格洛克公司的著名系列
真的非常荣幸
Again, it's an honor.
自80年代推出的G17以来
…我们为大国服务的…
...of our stewardship of this great...
已经装备了40多个国家的军警
那个黑人是谁？ 他是埃塞俄比亚大主教
- That our guy in the collar? - The Archbishop of Ethiopia.
来接受奖章，你知道的？
He's getting a medal. Know it?
非洲之角*，我知道 *指索马里半岛，非洲东北部呈犀牛角状的地区，地理位置重要，冲突不断
HOA. Horn of Africa. Yeah.
我在那工作过
You know I worked there?
“枪杀平民时你的 第一感觉是什么？”
You know what they say about the first thing that you feel
知道他们怎么说吗？
when you shoot a civilian, right?
“枪的后坐力”？ 没错
- Recoil of your rifle? - Right.
真有创意
That's very original.
谢谢大主教分享 如此有启发性的演讲
Thank you, Archbishop, for those inspiring words.
下面是总统讲话了
The President speaks next.
各小组准备行动
All teams stand by.
吉布森特工 报告收到，一切正常
Agent Gibson, we read your fly-by. Situation all clear, over.
詹姆斯特工，一切正常
Agent James, all clear.
现在我感到很荣幸…
Now it gives me enormous pleasure...
风速每小时三英里 …向大家介绍接下来的嘉宾
- Got wind at three, full value. - ... to introduce to you
有请美国总统
the President of the United States.
风向正中，修正角四点五度
Make it four-and-a-half minutes of angle.
静风修正三密耳
Three-mil hold, in case the wind dies.
刺客上膛了
He's loaded.
正在计算高度、湿度还有温度
Altitude, humidity, temperature accounted for.
…本市曾是国都…
In the city that was the capital of...
我们要赶快解决他
We got to take him.
还有十秒
Ten seconds.
风向正好对他有利 马上动手吧
Wind matches his setup. Take him! Take him now!
派出紧急反应小队 快解决他…
Send in the ERT team. Take out the...
有人开枪！
Shots fired! Shots fired!
闪光倒下了！闪光倒下了
Flashlight is down, Flashlight is down.
什么？闪光倒下了？ 重复一遍，闪光倒下了
- What? Flashlight down? - I say again. Flashlight is down.
总统中弹了 情报很混乱…
- The President has been shot. - There's mass confusion...
总统中弹了是吗？
Has the President been shot?
枪手在教堂顶部
Right at the church steeple.
你怎么会失手？
How could you miss?
你他妈的怎么会失手？
How could you fucking miss?
三十秒内撤离现场，快去追
Thirty seconds, clear out. Chase him down.
他受伤了，干掉他
He's bleeding. Kill him.
指挥所呼叫秃鹰二号，马上出击
Command Post to Condor Two, load up, over.
秃鹰二号正在准备
Condor Two loading up.
快，快
Go, go, go, go, go!
SOPMOD M4
快点，大伙！
Hurry up, guys. Come on.
Cheytac Intervention M200
秃鹰二号，指挥所呼叫 等候新命令
Condor Two, this is Command Post. Stand by for update, over.
待命，完毕
Standing by, over.
指挥所
Command Post!
指挥所，十九号呼叫
Command Post! Command Post, this is Post 19.
听到我说话吗？
You guys read me?
我是否原地待命？ 求你…
- Should I hold post? - Please.
帮帮我，他们向我开枪
Please help me. Please. They shot me.
我是 FBI，举起手来 求你帮我
- FBl. Put your hands up! - Please. Hey.
GLOCK 23
救我一命
Save me.
GLOCK23是22的缩小型，相当于GLOCK19的点40S&W口径型
说什么？
What?
被FBI大量采购
车钥匙给我
Give me the keys.
我没枪杀总统 我被提蒙斯陷害了
I didn't shoot the President. Timmons was a setup.
来人！
Help!
我是 FBI，他抢了我的枪和车
FBl! Took my weapon and my car.
别担心，他被我击中了两枪 你没事吗？
Don't worry, I already shot him twice. You all right?
指挥所，能否描述嫌疑犯特征？
CP, 17, can you repeat possible suspect description?
不能，没有进一步信息
Negative, no further at this time.
指挥所，十五号呼叫 我这里一切正常
CP, this is 15. No activity at my location.
随时可以转移位置
I am available to move if necessary.
明白
Copy that.
我是提蒙斯警官 请求支援
This is Officer Timmons requesting backup.
我在追捕刺杀嫌疑犯
Pursuing suspect in assassination.
他抢了一辆 FBI 警车 沿宝石街向南逃窜
Now fleeing in stolen FBl vehicle, moving south on Front from Diamond.
他持有武器，非常危险 我重复
Suspect is armed and dangerous. I repeat,
疑犯持有武器，非常危险
suspect is armed and dangerous.
费城全体警务人员注意
All Philly PD units be advised,
疑犯驾驶 FBI 警车逃逸
assassination suspect is fleeing in a stolen FBl vehicle.
正沿宝石街向南 往前沿大街逃窜
He is going south on Front from Diamond.
秃鹰二号呼叫，正前往前沿大街
This is Condor 2. We are transitioning from roadhouse to Front Street.
请提供嫌疑犯车辆详细情况
Please advise for further description of suspect vehicle.
指挥所，419 呼叫 我正沿着汤姆森大街向南前进
Dispatch, 419, I'm heading south on Thompson.
请告知车辆颜色或者其他特征
Do we have a color, anything on the vehicle?
嫌疑犯的车辆…
Assassination suspect's vehicle
为 06 款黑色福特皇冠 政府公用车
is one government-issue black 2006 Ford Crown Vic.
宾夕法尼亚州执照号码： 7317 JDE，完毕
Pennsylvania license number 7-3-1-7 James David Edward, over.
嫌疑犯最后出现的位置在哪里
What was suspect's last known location? Over.
在前沿大街南面
Last known is south on Front.
这里是詹姆斯特工 嫌疑犯为多人还是一人？
This is Agent James. Do we have multiple suspects or a single suspect?
詹姆斯特工，不能告知 暂时没有进一步资料
Agent James, negative. No further information...
这里是皮特曼特工 车辆沿卡斯特大街高速行驶
This is Agent Pittman. Car seen going high speed on Castor.
沿卡斯特大街高速行驶，请注意
High speed on Castor. Be advised.
是提蒙斯报警的吗？
Timmons called it in?
是的，完全按计划
Right on time, like he was supposed to.
只是没来得及补上一枪 是…但他身中两枪
- Before he shot him again. - Yeah, well, he's been hit twice,
除非他有本事自己止血
so unless he can stop the bleeding without going to the hospital or a doctor,
否则他活不了多久
it doesn't really matter.
不出二十分钟就会发现 他死在某个街角的垃圾桶旁
They're going to find him lying dead by a dumpster in an alley in 20 minutes.
你的位置在哪？
What is your location?
嫌疑犯车辆为 黑色轿车，四门…
Suspect vehicle a black sedan, four-door...
所有单位请注意
All units be advised,
有目击者报告嫌疑犯进入位于…
eyewitness reports suspect vehicle entering High-Tech Car Wash
杰拉德大街和九号街 西北角的自动洗车房
on the northwest corner of Girard and 9th, over.
指挥所请注意
Command Post be advised,
秃鹰二号正在赶往嫌疑犯所在位置
this is Condor Two en route to suspect location, over.
指挥所，秃鹰三号马上赶到
Command Post, Condor Three copies. All en route.
哟，伙计 小心点伙计
- Yo, man! - Watch it, man!
靠…
Shit!
指挥所，秃鹰二号 和三号进入拦截位置
Command Post, Condors Two and Three moving to intercept, over.
嫌疑犯车辆在九十五号 桥底与卡车相撞
Suspect vehicle collided with a truck under the 95.
他位于市场街与哥伦布大街交界
He's at Market and Columbus.
情况不错，车辆受损停下了 重复，车辆受损停下了
Looks good. Vehicle is disabled. Repeat, vehicle disabled.
干掉他，开枪！
Take him down! Fire!
发现一辆福特皇冠车 黑色，政府牌照
I got a Crown Vic. Black. Government plates.
前排座位有尸体吗？
Dead guy in the front seat?
马上给我开始封锁三十英里长的河道
I want the banks of this river lined for 30 miles, five minutes ago.
往下游搜索
All right. Let's start the search downriver.
我正在采访提蒙斯警官 他徒步追捕了嫌疑犯
I'm here with Officer Timmons, who pursued the suspect on foot.
警官，可以告诉我们事发经过吗？
Officer, can you tell us what happened?
嫌疑犯身份目前已经确定为…
The would-be assassin, tentatively identified
退役陆战队枪炮军士 鲍勃・李・史瓦格
as retired Marine Gunnery Sergeant Bob Lee Swagger,
数千名州警和联邦警察正在 动员起来对他进行围追堵截
is being pursued by thousands of State and Federal law enforcement personnel
as we speak.
警方布下了天罗地网 但没发现史瓦格的踪迹
As the net begins to tighten nationwide, there is still no trace of Swagger.
仅仅在德拉瓦河底…
Nothing but an abandoned car has been found
发现了被遗弃的汽车
at the bottom of the Delaware River.
服役七年的费城资深 警官史丹利・提蒙斯…
Seven-year veteran Philadelphia police officer Stanley Timmons,
最早赶到事发现场
first to respond to the scene,
并开了三枪把史瓦格打伤
is believed to have shot and injured Swagger.
据报道，他至少被枪击中两次
Early reports indicate that the assailant
may have been hit as many as two times.
同时，FBI 不愿对…
Meanwhile, the FBl has been unwilling to comment
其手下一名特工受到史瓦格攻击并被缴械…
on information that an agent of theirs
随后又被其抢走车辆逃离现场…
was assaulted and disarmed by Swagger as he fled the scene,
一事发表评论
possibly in a stolen FBl vehicle.
目前，尚未有史瓦格的任何消息
At this time, no sign of Swagger has been found.
你让我们感到非常难堪
You have embarrassed this office.
局里的风纪调查处门 将对你进行严格的审查
You will be facing a review from the Office of Professional Responsibility.
长官？
Sir...
我并不感到难堪
Well, I don't feel embarrassed.
他是陆战队强侦连狙击手…
A Force Recon Marine Scout Sniper
而我刚从警校毕业三个星期
disarmed me three weeks out of the academy.
我能活着就很不错了
If anything, I feel lucky to be alive.
为何他要说自己没杀总统？
Why'd he say he didn't shoot the President?
因为他没打中
Because he didn't.
他还说提蒙斯陷害他
Also, he said Timmons was a setup.
他没这样说
He never said that.
一个市警能把他打伤两次
City cop managed to spot, shoot this guy twice.
令你很丢脸
You got your ass kicked.
你记错了
You're misremembering.
在极度压力下是常有的事
That's normal under extreme stress events.
你刚才所说的要作为正式记录吗？
Have you given your official statement yet?
要是我就会说话谨慎
Because I would be very cautious about what went in it.
也许我该等调查报告 出来后再回忆一下
Well, maybe I should wait for the report to come out, read it and then remember.
你相信那家伙吗？
Can you believe this fucking guy?
这就对了
There you go.
什么事？ 新的情报送来了
- Yes? - The raw feeds are in
是电视台消息
from the networks.
情报有了意外进展 华盛顿特区…
...development, security camera footage from Washington, D.C.
以及费城一些监控 摄像机画面显示…
and several locations in Philadelphia
嫌疑犯鲍勃・李・史瓦格军士…
shows the suspect, Gunnery Sergeant Bob Lee Swagger,
曾去过那些地方，寻找 射击位置并记录风向数据
scouting shooting locations, traveling and taking wind readings.
尽管警方在全国范围内加紧搜捕 但仍未发现史瓦格的踪影
As the net begins to tighten nationwide, there is still no trace of Swagger.
对不起
Excuse me.
刚刚停电了，不能营业了
Can't sell you nothing. Just lost our power.
我付现金，不用找零钱
Please. I got cash, and you can keep the change.
可我没办法找东西
Ain't gonna be able to find nothing.
我只需要注射针头、盐、 糖
Please, all I need is a marinade needle, some salt, some sugar,
还有一些水
couple bottles of water.
要多少？
How many?
先生对不起，我感到很遗憾
Well, sir, I'm sorry. I'm sorry to hear that.
我敢肯定她是个非常虔诚的基督徒
I'm sure she's a really nice Christian woman
但我们不处理此类事务
but we don't take care of those things here.
好吧… FBI 公布了一个录像
- Yeah. Okay, well... - The FBl released a video letter...
去咨询专家吧 …威胁要取总统性命
- ... see a counselor. - ... threatening the life of the President...
可以联系《菲尔博士》*或类似的，好的 *美国著名脱口秀节目
Dr. Phil or something. Okay.
是十天前鲍勃・李・史瓦格寄出的
...signed and dated by Bob Lee Swagger just 10 days ago.
联邦特工搜查了怀俄明风河地区
Federal agents today executed a search warrant
in the Wind River range of Wyoming
史瓦格在那里居住过数年时间
where Swagger had been living for several years.
同时，FBI 一直不愿对…
In the meantime, the FBl has been unwilling to comment,
史瓦格下落不明的事情发表评论
as no sign of Swagger has been found.
有线索了吗？ 没
- Get anything? - No.
好的，在什么地方？
Yeah, wait, wait. Where was this?
还有呢？
And? Yes?
她怀疑就是他，不过 当时停电周围很黑
She thinks it was him, but it was dark because the power was out in the store.
他买了什么？ 最好没错
- What'd he buy? - Gotta be.
盐、糖、水和注射针头
Salt, sugar, water, and a marinade injector.
这家伙想吃烧烤？
Guy going to a barbecue.
盐水注射针头可以用来打点滴
Salt, water, an injector could be used for an IV,
可糖用来干什么？
but what's with the sugar?
等一下！
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Hold that! Hold that!
糖在战场上一直用来处理伤口
Well, sugar's been used to treat battlefield wounds
已经有几百年历史
for hundreds of years.
当然必须依靠渗透压力才行
It has something to do with osmotic pressure.
这在拿破仑战争中司空见惯
It was popular during the Napoleonic War.
你在报告中提到拿破仑战争
You go into Howard's office with the Napoleonic War,
霍华德局长会送你去精神病院
he's gonna put you on psych leave.
回去办公，别让自己毁了
Go back to your desk. I'm saving your life.
其中一点…
One thing is...
…一七九零年到一八零零年…
...1790 to 1800.
其中一点…
One thing is...
（温布尔登杯赢家）
肯塔基州，基尼市
打扰了，夫人
I'm sorry to bother you, ma'am.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你是鲍勃・李・史瓦格 唐尼以前的拍档
You're Bob Lee. Swagger. Donnie's old partner.
我没枪杀总统
Look, I didn't shoot the President.
我知道
I know.
你知道？
You do?
死的不是总统 是埃塞俄比亚大主教
The President's not dead. Ethiopian Archbishop is.
谁会想杀他啊？
Why in the hell would somebody want to shoot him?
你是护士吧？
Look, you're a nurse, right?
不，那只是唐尼的愿望 我晕血
No. No, that was Donnie's dream. I couldn't stand the blood.
我是小学教师
I teach the third grade.
帮帮我 你应该离开
- Please. - Look, you should go.
帮帮我
Please.
Please?
我是被陷害的
I didn't do whatever they said I did.
我发誓
I swear.
我遇到麻烦了，需要帮助
I'm in some bad trouble and I need some help.
我不会跑那么远来对你撒谎的
I wouldn't have come all the way here to lie to you.
你打算朝我开枪？
You still figuring on shooting me?
那霰弹枪太长了，不方便
Only that shotgun's a little long to bring up fast.
如果要下手就快点
Look, if you're going to do it, just get it over with.
我走投无路了
I ain't got nowhere else to go.
把车停到车库，邻居很快会起床
Pull the truck in the garage. The neighbors'll be up in a minute.
叫我莎拉
You'd best call me Sarah.
好的
All right.
警察局，请问有什么事？
911, what's your emergency?
你好？
Hello?
这里是警察局 我们刚才接到你的电话
This is 911. We received a hang-up from this location.
邻居的狗碰倒了垃圾桶
Yeah, neighbor's dog knocked over the trash cans
吓了我一跳 现在没事了，谢谢了
and scared the hell out of me. Everything's fine. Thanks.
那就好
Okay, then.
如果打电话报警不说话
Seems you call the police and hang up without saying anything,
他们会很负责的打过来询问
they call you back right away.
我早就应该来看你
I should've come and seen you in person.
应该在出事之前
Before. I mean, then.
我收到你的信了
Yeah, I read the letter.
没关系
It was okay.
还有你每年寄来的花
And once a year I got the flowers.
你看来很糟
You don't look real good.
我这回是大难不死，我撑了一晚
I'm supposed to be dead. Been a long night.
怎么逃出来的？
Why aren't you?
美国政府花了大量时间金钱
Well, the U.S. government spent a lot of time and money
教会我如何死里逃生
teaching me how not to die
当然也教会我如何杀人
after they got done teaching me how to kill people.
你想让我帮你什么？
So how is it I'm supposed to help you?
你会用十字绣针法 帮我把伤口缝一下吗？
You can do a running cross-stitch, finish it with an embroidery knot?
会
Yeah.
最好去不同商店买
You got to try to spread it out.
集中购买容易引起怀疑
It's gonna look odd you buy it all in one place.
一幅外科手套、两瓶酒精、两尺长的导管 一包厨房海绵、热水瓶、两把手术剪刀…
这三年怎么感觉像十年一样漫长？
How can it be three years ago when it seems like ten?
因为我们很痛苦
Mileage can be rough.
竟然还有比我早的
No one ever beats me in.
你没回家？
You never left.
局里的人都认为我疯了
Everyone keeps telling me I'm crazy.
好像我看见的听见的都是假的
Like I didn't see what I saw, or heard what I heard.
我没疯，你觉得呢？
I'm not crazy, though. You think I'm crazy?
这些情报从哪得到的？
Where did all this stuff come from?
一开始我以为是来自华盛顿附近的匡提科* *FBI学院，也是海军陆战队训练基地之一
At first I thought it was Washington, Quantico.
结果不是这么回事 像变魔术一样送来了
I checked and it didn't. It just magically arrived.
他们来自一些协助机构，如烟酒枪支管理局 国家侦察局还有不知名的部门
Cooperating agencies, ATF, NRO, places that don't even have initials
他们在出现紧急状况时提供合作
they cooperate in times of national emergency.
你需要休息一下了
You need to get some sleep.
要知道枪击发生后二十二分钟
You know that the first ballistics diagram got here
这里就获得了第一张弹道图
22 minutes after the shooting.
我们工作效率高
We're good at our jobs.
十二分钟时，警方派出了直升机
12 minutes after the shooting, they were still scrambling choppers.
并且封锁了现场
The scene was locked down.
他们是怎么在随后的 十分钟内完成检测的？
How did they get a reverse azimuth 10 minutes after that?
我们是吃官饭的
I mean, we work for the federal government.
不会有那么高效率
We're not that good at our jobs.
想看东西不？ 可能不想
- You want to see something? - Probably not.
这是我下载的
I downloaded this.
这是史瓦格两年前
This is a full-scale printout
在九百码射击目标的全尺寸图
of a target Swagger shot two years ago at 1,000 yards.
我在上面打了孔，那是一次比赛
I punched in the holes myself. It was at a competition.
我读过一篇文章说史瓦格 有百步穿杨的硬功夫
I read an article. It said Swagger shot a silver dollar at a grand.
五发子弹
Five shots,
在一千码距离
at 1,000 yards,
落点范围只有一英寸半 一英寸半！
an inch-and-a-half spread. An inch and a half!
…这城市曾经是国都…
It was the capital of the United States...
那是总统身后的旗子 几乎纹丝不动
That's the flag behind the President. It's barely waving.
这是国家气象局给出的
This is the wind speed and direction
事发时的风速和风向数据
according to the National Weather Service
我测算了一下
at the time of the shot. I did the math.
枪法那么精准的人…
Now, how does a man who can do that
在两千码距离射击竟然偏2.5英尺
miss by two-and-a-half feet at 2,000 yards?
我不明白
I don't get it.
你熬了一整夜 别管它了，去睡吧
You've had a long night. Let it go and get some sleep.
我看了提蒙斯的采访
You know, I saw Timmons interviewed.
他说当时在步行巡逻
He said he was walking foot patrol,
看到有步枪从窗口伸了出来
saw a rifle barrel sticking out of a window,
于是上去检查，他向史瓦格开枪
went upstairs to investigate, and shot Swagger.
狙击手是绝不会把枪伸出窗外的
No sniper sticks his rifle out of a window.
他们会在隐蔽处射击
They shoot from cover, back in the room.
这完全不合逻辑
It doesn't make any sense.
我要去找提蒙斯谈谈 你不能谈
- I'm gonna talk to Timmons. - No, you're not.
为什么？他们真开除我？
Why? 'Cause they're gonna fire me if I do?
提蒙斯昨晚在巷子里 被抢劫犯杀死了
Timmons was killed by a mugger in an alley last night.
搞阴谋总离不开杀人灭口
In a conspiracy, all loose ends are trimmed.
就像杰克・路比打死了奥斯华德*？ *刺杀肯尼迪的凶手被灭口
Jack Ruby shoots Oswald?
好人不一定有好报
Bad things happen to good people.
可这也太快了
Yeah, not that quick, they don't.
我暂时把血止住了
Well, I stopped the bleeding temporarily.
不过恐怕还会再流
But it'll cut loose again.
我只能延缓感染的发生 你必须帮我…
I held off the worst of the infection, but you're gonna have to open it up,
把创伤清理干净
cut out and scrub away anything that's dead,
然后把伤口再缝上
working your way out, sewing it together
千万注意不能发生二次感染
and you got to try to make sure you don't re-infect it.
准备好了吗？
You ready for this?
我吸了一氧化氮后就会昏过去
I'm going to do all those Whip-It!'s and pass out.
祝你成功
Good luck, okay?
我需要你制订一个刺杀总统的计划
I need you to plan a presidential assassination.
那个黑人是谁？
That our guy in the collar?
哪国总统？
Whose president?
我没有叫你执行
I didn't say 'execute'.
来接受奖章，你知道的？
He's getting a medal. Know it?
埃塞俄比亚大主教
The Archbishop of Ethiopia.
你必须找到那枪手
You need to find the shooter.
不
No.
两天半时间身中两枪 竟然找不到？
Two-and-a-half days, shot twice, no sign?
必须找到他
Find me something.
也许他钻进某个地洞里死了
Maybe he crawled into a hole and died.
他没死
He's not dead.
对他进行全面调查
Tear apart his life.
再查
Again.
成功了？
Go okay?
我一直在做梦
I've been hallucinating.
我得告诉你一件事
Something I need to tell you.
来福死了
Ralphie's dead.
谁是来福？
Who's Ralphie?
他们说你把狗杀了
Well, they said you shot your dog
因为知道自己有去无回
'cause you knew you weren't coming back.
他们说的？
They said that, huh?
它叫山姆
Name was Sam.
是条好狗，我把它从小养大的
He was a good dog. I raised him from a pup.
你还好吗？
You okay?
不
No.
你有什么打算？
What are you gonna do?
我要先养好伤
I'll get better.
然后查清事情真相
Then I'm going to burn their playhouse down.
哪种武器系统要求脚架的尺寸是43*43*29英寸？
简单，M3可支撑多种枪械，最多到50口径重机枪
这种系统为什么要接上100米长1/4英寸宽的电缆？
有何贵干？
Can I help you?
看看这个网站：www.precisionremotes.com
陷阱式T-250D战术遥控系统
别动
Hold still.
我一直想问你
I been meaning to ask you.
你有男朋友吗？
You have a boyfriend?
怎么？
Why?
难道要我一辈子守寡？
Am I still supposed to be the grieving widow?
唐尼去世三年了
It's been three years.
不
No.
我只想知道，如果有人擅自闯入…
Just wonder if I'm gonna have to shoot somebody
我是否应该朝他开枪
walks through that door without knocking,
wondering where you've been.
没有
Well, no.
目前没有稳定的男朋友
Nothing steady. No boyfriend.
还不错嘛
Not bad.
只是伤口有点僵硬
A little stiff, but...
嘿
Hey.
你可以当一名好护士
You know, you would've made one hell of a nurse.
你表现得非常勇敢
That was really brave, what you did.
你救了我
You saved my life.
我好点了，我该走了
I'm better. I better get to it.
他们绝不会停止寻找你的
They're never gonna stop chasing you.
相信我
Never.
他们绝不会放过你
They're never gonna stop looking.
除了找我他们还会找另外一个人
In the meantime, they need someone else to find.
我会把他送入虎口
I'm going to give them him.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
很可能收到一石二鸟的效果
May be a way to get two birds with that stone, too.
史瓦格？ 嘿
- Swagger? - Hey.
这是唐尼小时候的猎枪
The gun Donnie learned to hunt with when he was a kid.
看着不起眼，但非常准
It ain't much, but it shoots true.
我藏起它之前擦过和上过油
I cleaned and oiled it before I put it away.
给我？
You sure?
是的
Yeah.
当初他们来找你时…
Why'd you go?
为何答应他们？
When they came to see you.
他们知道我的弱点
They know which buttons to press.
我过于轻信别人 只要你说出你是爱国者
I'm still enough of a sucker, you press that patriot button,
我就会说“要我干什么都行”
I'll sit up in my chair and say, 'Which way you want me to go, boss?'
我不认为这值得骄傲 但也不觉得羞耻
I mean, I ain't real proud of it, but I ain't ashamed, either.
我有个计划
You know, I got a plan,
可能需要你的帮助
but I think I'm going to need your help.
好的，我会帮你
Okay. I'll do it.
可我还没说要干什么
I haven't even told you what it is yet.
我知道
I know.
听着
Look.
都怪我不好
It was my fault.
什么？
What?
如果不是我 唐尼一定不会死
You know, with Donnie. I should never have...
什么？
What?
你怎么敢这么说？
Don't you dare.
你不能把责任都揽到自己身上
Don't you try and take that away from him.
他知道为什么参军
He knew exactly what he was doing when he enlisted.
参加侦察兵狙击手训练的时候 也知道自己在做什么
He knew exactly what he was doing
when he enrolled in scout sniper training.
他热爱自己的职业
He loved what he did.
没人强迫他
No one made him do it.
你不必感到内疚
That ain't yours to carry.
好吧
You're right.
对不起，是我不好
I'm sorry I tried.
没事的
It's okay.
我需要你找一个 FBI 探员
I need you to meet with this FBl agent.
利用他把约翰逊引出来
Use him to flush Johnson out of his hiding place.
你只要告诉他车辆识别码 他就会按课本上教他的去做
Give him the vehicle ID number. He'll do what he's trained to do.
然后你就马上离开 别被他们抓住
You get in and get out. Don't get caught.
抓住了你就等于抓住了我
You get caught, I get caught.
知道这是什么吗？
You know what that is?
他说没开枪杀人，可我怎么知道？
Says he didn't shoot no one, but I don't know.
他和我在一起
Well, he's been staying with me.
谁和你在一起？ 鲍勃・李・史瓦格？
Who's been staying with you? Bob Lee Swagger?
车子的牌照或许是假的 但这号码肯定是真的
The plates are probably fake. Pretty sure the other number's real.
这是什么？ 车辆识别码
- And what is this? - A VIN number.
谁也不会闲着没事去改它
Seems no one goes through the trouble to change them anymore.
你要老老实实坐在这 等我走远了再离开
And you're going to sit real still until I'm long gone.
看到那个穿飞鹰夹克的人了吗？
See the guy in the Eagles jacket?
对不起，先生，请你出示你的身份证
Excuse me, sir. Can I see some ID, please?
先生，请摘下你的帽子
Sir, I'm going to need you to take off your hat
出示你的身份证
and show me some ID.
请你按照我的要求做
I'm not gonna ask you again.
摘下帽子，混蛋
Take your hat off, asshole!
伯莱塔M92FS
Get on the ground! Get your ass on the ground!
趴在地上！趴在地上！
属于意大利伯莱塔公司70年代末的M9系列
美国陆军大量采购，但评价不高
嘿，近来还好吗
Hey, how's it going?
嘿，约翰
Hey, John.
未经许可，禁止入内
共有1个文档符合此号码
喂，艾德
- Hey, Ed? - Yeah.
你拿了斯蒂芬的文件吗？ 我要拿回来
You got that Stevens file we wanted back?
被隔离信息，需要D 级别*通行证 *美国国防部最高警戒级别
你真的这么想知道？ 可能会被开除的
How badly do you want to know? Because this will get you fired.
再过四十五分钟…
Well, I have to go before the Office of Professional Responsibility
我就要去风纪调查处接受审查了
in 45 minutes for a review.
反正我都会被开除的 我豁出去了
I'm gonna get fired anyway. I'm done worrying about that.
你认为呢？
What do you think?
我认为 CNN 在我们之前 搞到了录像带
I think that CNN got the tapes before we did,
通过剪辑来展现射击角度
already edited together to show the angles.
谁交给他们的？
Who delivered them?
是一个始终保持沉默的 秘密机构干的
An unnamed agency who will never confirm or deny.
这一次他们否认，实际上…
They denied, which is a...
就等于他们已经承认了
Which is a confirmation of sorts.
承认什么？
Of what?
你的问题已经超过了 自己应该知道的范围了
That you are asking questions way outside your pay grade.
别这样，快告诉我
Oh, come on, just tell me.
你不会想接受他们的调查的
You don't want to be here for that review.
他们不仅可以开除你 还可以起诉你、拘留你
They don't have to stop at firing you. They can charge you and hold you.
主管特别助理有 D 级通行证
The ASAC's job comes with Delta clearance.
谢谢 快走
- Thank you. - Go.
这是一个网络的聊天记录
This is a copy of a chat room transcript.
他们无所不谈 开始我并没有太在意
These guys talk about everything. I didn't give it much thought at the time.
我们利用 WiFi 网络 跟踪到一家甜品店
We just traced it to a donut shop with free WiFi.
这是七分钟之前费城 FBI 分局 提出的 D 级通行证申请
But this, this is a Delta-level clearance request
out of the FBl field office in Philadelphia seven minutes ago.
谷歌地图显示那家甜品店…
Funny thing, Google Maps puts the donut shop
就在费城分局的三个街区外
only three blocks away from the field office.
史瓦格消失以前只有一个人见过他
There's only one guy who met with Swagger before he disappeared.
他住在费城
He lives in Philly.
为 FBI 工作
And he works for the FBl.
尼古拉斯・孟菲斯
Nicholas Memphis.
那是一家很奇怪的公司 跟许多大企业有生意往来
...really strange company. Contracts with a lot of the Fortune 500.
在弗吉尼亚和特拉华有分支机构 注册地在巴拿马
Offices in Virginia, Delaware, registered in Panama.
他们有条船悬挂利比亚国旗
They own a boat that's flagged out of Libya.
他们绝对不是政府机构
They're definitely not government,
但有军方背景
but they have high ex-military contacts like you wouldn't believe.
他们是承包商
These are contractors.
我也不能告诉你 这公司是做什么的，但…
I can't tell what this company does, but...
嘿
Hey.
嘿，嘿，嘿！
Hey, hey, hey!
孟菲斯？
Memphis?
孟菲斯！
Memphis!
这家伙什么也不知道
For a man who didn't know much,
没必要再折腾下去了
you sure took a long, painful time to tell it.
给他灌点水
Get him some water.
好
Good.
想撒尿了没？
Got to pee yet?
把胃里的药物排泄干净
Got to flush them drugs out of your system.
免得你自杀后引起怀疑
Look awful suspicious if you were to go and shoot yourself
我们这里吃的都是一种药
pumped full of the same shit the agency uses.
我不会自杀的！
I'm not going to shoot myself.
你会的
Sure you will.
带他过去，准备好
Take him out. Get him ready.
不！
No!
那是我的枪
That's my gun.
是的
Yeah.
你还写了份感人的遗书
You wrote a real touching suicide note, too.
写满了你对错误的悔恨
All overwrought with guilt about your mistakes.
挣扎也没用
Quit your struggling.
这办法很有效 我们不是第一次用了
This thing works. It's not the first time we've used it.
罗素！罗素！
Russo. Russo!
戴维斯快来！
Davis, get out here!
我说你们还在磨蹭什么？
What is the goddamn hold-up?
请不要杀我！ 请不要杀我！我相信你！
Don't kill me, please! Don't kill me! I believe you!
杀你？
Kill you?
要杀我早杀了
Had enough chances. I wanted you dead, you'd be dead.
哪个混蛋发明了这玩意？
What kind of asshole'd think up a thing like this?
这个小口径步枪和 简易消声器还挺好用嘛
Not bad with a poodle shooter and a makeshift silencer, huh?
帮我把他们扔到水里
Help me toss these boys in the water?
原来是你设的圈套！
You set me up and you used me as bait!
是的，但他们真的就照做了
You think? Flushed them out, didn't it?
我本来想留个活口
I was kind of hoping to keep one alive,
但他们真的想杀你
but they were kind of determined to kill you.
你可以请个好律师 我给局里打电话
You can hire a good lawyer, and I'll call the Bureau.
可以和他们协商
They can work out some kind of deal.
你可以向他们证明主教不是你杀的
This is explainable. You can prove that you didn't shoot the Archbishop.
看来你还是不明白
I don't think you understand.
那些人杀了我的狗
These boys killed my dog.
现在是二十一世纪 你不可以跟他们这样硬拼
Hey, this is the 21st century. You can't go to war with these people.
最终还是要法律…
In the end, the law is all...
法律绝对不会把他们怎么样
In the end, the law'll never catch and hold them.
不出一两年，他们就会重操旧业
In a year or two, they'll be back in business.
改头换面，继续做恶 重振旗鼓
New names, new messenger boys, same old story.
只有我会死
And I'll be dead.
所以我还要想出一条活路
It's gonna be some hard, hairy work, Pork.
血还要流，人还会死
There's gonna be more shooting, and more people are gonna die.
我别无选择，只能把这件事做到底
Now, I didn't start it, but be sure as hell I mean to see it through.
只说你是合作还是不合作？
So you get it straight. You in or you out?
我今天没赶上一个会议
You know, I missed a meeting today
在那个会议上我会被开除
where I was going to get fired for unprofessional conduct
因为遭到了这群不存在的人的绑架
because I was kidnapped by people that don't exist.
我抬他的腿
I'll take his legs.
这就对了，菜鸟
It's a good call, Pork.
你想说一个 FBI 菜鸟特工
You're trying to tell me a rookie FBl agent
杀了他们三个？
overpowered and killed the three of them?
不
No.
他们是被人从两百码外开枪打死的
They were shot from a distance of about 200 yards.
用点二二口径的步枪
With a.22.
史瓦格还活着 是的
- Swagger's alive. - Yes.
那个年轻的 FBI 特工
And that young kid,
FBl Agent
尼克・孟菲斯
Nick Memphis,
他已经设法窃取了 D 级通行证
who managed to pry out a Delta-level clearance,
他没有返回局里 目前还和史瓦格呆在一起
hasn't come back to the office and is out there with him.
怎么样？
What?
我刚查了史瓦格的信用卡
I just went over Swagger's financials again.
他每年定期给一个人寄鲜花
Once a year, he sent flowers to someone with his Visa card.
我侵入了FTD*的数据库，找到了地址 *世界最悠久、最大的鲜花快递公司
I cracked the FTD database, got an address.
是在唐尼・佛恩的祭日 寄给他的遗孀
Donnie Fenn's widow. Anniversary of his death.
这个女人又改用了以前的姓
She went back to using her maiden name,
所以当初调查的时候给漏掉了
which is why we missed it the first time.
估计她是世界上唯一一个
She's maybe the only person in the entire world
对史瓦格言听计从的人了
that would believe anything that Swagger had to say.
你看，肯塔基州基尼市
Look. Keene City, Kentucky.
开车一会就到
It's just within driving range.
开车太慢了，我们坐飞机去 好
- What are you waiting for? Take the jet. - All right.
这是和史瓦格的战争
We've given Swagger a new war,
他又有了观察员
he's found a new spotter.
事情变得非常难办了
This is about to get worse.
田纳西州，雅典市
好像到了
I think we're here.
史瓦格
Hey. Swagger.
我们到了
I think we're here.
欢迎回到田纳西
Welcome to Tennessee.
这里可是枪战之乡
Patron state of shooting stuff.
那个人是谁？
Hey, who is this guy?
他是密西西比的传奇人物
This guy was the greatest gunsmith east of the Mississippi. He's a legend.
He knows more about guns and the people who shoot them
比史密斯威森枪厂*知道得还多 *美国最大的手枪制造商
than Smith % Wesson.
不过别担心 他要杀我们三英里外就动手了
Don't really matter anymore. He knew we were coming the last three miles.
注意礼貌 好的
- You mind your manners. - All right.
两位远道而来，想找什么？
You boys come a long way. What you looking for?
智慧
Wisdom.
你们可能找错了地方
You come to the wrong place.
可能吧
Maybe.
如果有人想让一支步枪射出的子弹
Say a man wanted to fire a bullet from one rifle
和另外一支步枪的子弹完全相同
and have it match exactly to another.
能做到吗？
Could that be done?
坐
Take a seat.
请坐，先生
Have a chair, son.
如果你能使步枪的 子弹射出没有留下痕迹
If you could get a bullet that had been shot clean through the first rifle,
就可以在上面伪造槽纹
could make the grooves match.
很久都没人这么做了
Kind of thing ain't been done in a long time, though.
从大主教身上取下的子弹
The bullet that was taken out of the Archbishop
已经严重变形
was completely mangled on impact.
FBI 只能做材质鉴别
FBl match was metallurgical.
谢谢，老太婆
Thank you, Mother.
但是那也不能保证万无一失 所以他们必须格外慎重
Yeah, but you couldn't guarantee that going in, so they had to be sure.
很难想象他们能够做到
And I still can't figure out how they could be.
味道不错？ 是啊
- Good coffee? - Yep.
在左边的书架上找找看 上数第二层
Look on your left, there. Second shelf down.
红色封皮的那本
Red leather spine.
作者的名字叫史高飞
Written by a guy named Schofeld.
我把它放在那里十五年了 没想到还用得上
Put it there 15 years ago. Don't figure it's moved since then.
第四章 改变子弹以达到不同效果　第一节 裹纸法
这里，裹纸法
Yeah. Paper patching.
始于一八七零年非洲的最新技术
State of the art. 1870s Africa.
用纸包裹子弹
Paper-wrapped bullet.
弹头不会和枪管直接接触
No metal on metal going down the barrel.
槽纹就能匹配 纸会在子弹飞出枪口时脱落
Grooves would match. Paper unwinds at the muzzle.
子弹不会留下任何痕迹
Leaves no traces when it hits.
你们的问题很有趣 希望你们满意
Interesting question, though. Hope I satisfied you.
我还有个问题
I got another one.
不出我所料
I thought you might.
假如我寻找一个能在 两千两百码外命中目标的人
Suppose I was looking for a man to make a 2,200-yard cold-bore shot.
有谁能办到？
Who's alive that could do that?
听说有人不久前进行过那样的射击
Seems I heard about a shot like that being made not too long ago.
据说那个人叫鲍勃・李・史瓦格
Said the guy's name was Bob Lee Swagger.
我不认识他，所以无法证实
Never met the man, so I wouldn't know him.
没错，他们是这么说的
Yeah, they said that, all right.
我还听说人造糖精不会致癌
They also said that artificial sweeteners were safe,
伊拉克有大规模杀伤武器
and WMDs were in Iraq,
安娜・妮科尔*为了爱情而结婚！ *著名艳星，嫁给了比自己大63岁的亿万富翁
and Anna Nicole married for love!
不过暗杀总归不是好事
Would've been a bad job to take, though.
怎么讲？
How come?
开枪的人恐怕自己也活不成
Whoever took that shot's probably dead now.
阴谋诡计都是这样收场
That's how a conspiracy works.
那些在“草丘”*上的杀手也没活过3个小时 *据传真正刺杀肯尼迪的凶手隐藏在其中的人群里
Them boys on the grassy knoll, they were dead within three hours.
他们的尸体被埋在得林瓜*附近沙漠的无名墓地下
Buried in the damn desert. Unmarked graves out past Terlingua.
你说的这些是真的么？
And you know this for a fact?
铁锹我还留着呢
Still got the shovel.
假如不是那个人干的呢？
Sake of argument, somebody other than him?
俄罗斯还有个人
There was a guy in Russia.
已被关进了监狱
They locked his ass up.
有一个在法国，已经死掉了
Another one in France. I know he's dead.
另外还有一个…
There was one guy,
可他早就金盆洗手了
but he don't shoot no more.
那是个极端残忍的家伙
A brutal son of a bitch.
其他人直接射杀 他先把人打伤
Most boys shoot to kill. He'd shoot to wound,
然后等他的朋友来救他
wait till his friends come to help,
一起杀掉
kill them too.
一次就干掉了四个
Turned one target into four.
男的，女的，儿童 杀过好几百人呢
Men, women, children. Killed them by the hundreds.
他的对手急于要他的命
The other side wanted him. Bad.
最后在一栋废弃的六层楼里找到了他
Finally narrowed his hide down to an abandoned six-story building.
那些人用了最极端的方法
They quit the subtle tactics.
他们动用了炮火支援
They called in an artillery strike.
整栋楼都没了
Leveled a square block.
他被活活的埋在里面
Brought the building down on his ass.
有人说他还是逃出去了
Some say he crawled out of there.
有人说他死了
Some say he died.
但没有人再提起他的消息
Never heard from him no more.
见鬼
Fuck me.
怎么？
What?
我曾见过这个人
I met the son of a bitch.
这个世界什么都可能发生 是吧，军士？
Yeah. The world ain't what it seems, is it, Gunnie?
不，先生
No, sir.
记住我的话
You keep that in mind.
当你自以为明白的时候
The moment you think you got it figured,
其实不然
you're wrong.
他的名字？
He got a name?
是我，尼克
Hey, it's me, Nick.
你知道自己闯了多大的祸么？
Do you have any idea how much trouble you're in?
知道 你还好吗？尼克，你在哪？
- Yeah. - Are you okay? Nick, where are you?
你最好不要知道
It's better I don't tell you.
有笔吗？
Look, do you have a pen?
我要你帮我找一个人 叫米开罗・斯泽比亚克
I need you to find someone. Mikhaylo Sczerbiak.
好的 你记下了么？
- Yeah. - You got it?
已经记下了
I got it.
这个名字好难拼啊
Man, this is hard to spell.
史瓦格会想尽一切办法
Swagger is going to go with what he knows.
去寻找那个开枪的人
He'll try to track the shooter.
那只是一厢情愿
He won't get far that way.
并非如此
Yes, he will.
什么意思？ 我们会帮他找到你
- How's that? - We're going to help him.
要抓狼就得放饵
Sometimes to catch a wolf, you need to tie the bait to a tree.
那饵下场会怎样？
And what happens to the bait?
很难讲
Hard to say.
有时候牺牲总是难免的
But that's the nature of being the bait.
（米开罗・斯泽比亚克）
我是尼克，找到他了吗？ 他在弗吉尼亚州
- Hey, it's Nick. Did you find him? - He's in Virginia.
我们原本以为搞定的事情
An end we thought was tied up
又出岔子了
came untied.
什么意思，上校？
Meaning, Colonel?
史瓦格还活着
Swagger is still alive.
还活着
Oh, my.
我现在需要一架海关免检的运输机
I need to land a transport plane without a customs check.
我本不想打听 不过你要用它装什么？
I'm certain I don't want to know, but what's on the plane?
我们用在埃塞俄比亚的人
Crew we used in Ethiopia.
二十四名杀手
Twenty-four good, hard men.
还有武器和装备
Weapons and gear.
只有二十四名？
Only 24?
必须除掉他
Do kill him.
这次只许成功
No loose ends this time.
晚安，上校
Night, Colonel.
晚安，参议员
Good night, Senator.
是谁？
Hello?
有人么？
Someone there?
SIG-SAUER P226或P228（画面昏暗，很难判断）
看看
Now look.
瑞士SIG公司80年代推出P226系列
看看你都做了些什么
Look what you've done now.
228为226的紧凑型
此系列虽然表现比伯莱塔92F系列出色，但价格偏高
把枪给我
Give me that.
我可不想让你伤着自己？
I don't want you to hurt yourself. Okay?
所以在军队订单上一直占劣势
但受到执法机构和特种作战单位的青睐
你的男朋友呢？
Where's your boyfriend?
弗吉尼亚州，林奇堡
如果是陷阱怎么办？
What if it's a trap?
就是陷阱
Oh, it's a trap.
陷阱处处有
Guaranteed. Every time.
问题是谁会掉进去？
Question is, for whom?
购物清单好了吗？ 是的
- You got your list, right? - Yep.
好，记住别买错
All right, you make sure you stick to it.
走吧
Let's go.
这些到底是干什么用的？
Okay, so what are these for again?
催泪弹，由我来遥控
Tear gas is going to be on my remote.
好
Right.
凝固汽油弹用在一层 铁管炸弹，用来对付其他人
Napalm on the first floor. Pipe bombs on the rest of them.
这些东西要轻拿轻放 它的杀伤半径是十五英尺
Gotta be very careful with these. It's got a 15-foot kill radius.
我们这是要干什么？
So what exactly are we getting ready for?
要干的事可多了
For as much as we can be.
雷明登700
雷明登700旋转后拉式枪机步枪自1962年推出…
你现在面对四个敌人
All right, you got four enemy combatants.
把他们消灭
Take them one by one.
就以其精确性和威力受到称赞
专心致志，别受环境的影响
Keep shooting. Don't let anything distract you.
它是世界上最强大的旋转后拉式枪机步枪
枪瞄：Leupold Mark4 M1
见鬼！
Fuck!
调整手轮很长，而且顶端有很大的防滑凸起
不是说过别受环境影响吗？
Didn't I say don't let anything distract you?
这样的设计即使戴上厚厚的手套也很容易使用
Slow is smooth, smooth is fast. Let's see it.
慢就是稳，稳就是快，再来
所以很适合在寒带地区使用
旋转手轮时会发出轻微的“咔嗒”声，方便在夜间使用
不，不
No. No.
这里就我们两个，宝贝
It's just you and me, baby.
不！
No!
一共有三名警卫
You got three guards.
一个在两点钟方向
One at your 2:00,
一个在十二点钟
12:00
一个在十点钟
and 10:00.
两点方向有人靠近
Danger close. 2:00,
就离你五十码
fifty yards.
H&K G36KE
G36步枪是德国H&K公司90年代初研制的
已经装备了德国联邦国防军、西班牙军队
以及大量国家的执法单位
G36K是G36步枪的卡宾版本（K是德语“卡宾”的首字母）
外貌特征是前护木是4个散热孔
G36KE则是G36K的出口型，比标准版少一个红点瞄具
一个在你正上方
You got one right on you.
距离二十码，正在向你靠近
20 yards and closing.
伯莱塔M92FS
去看看周围的情况
Go check the perimeter.
告诉大家保持警惕
And tell the others to stay alert.
是，长官
I'm on it. Right away, sir.
伯莱塔M92FS
史瓦格，屋顶还有一个
Swagger, you got one above you on the roof.
三个都干掉了？
You killed all three?
有四个
There were four.
告诉我约翰逊的真名 我要知道他为谁工作
I want Johnson's real name. I want to know who he works for.
为什么要大动干戈
I want to know why it was worth going through that much effort
杀掉大主教？
to kill the Archbishop.
是你杀的吗？
Aren't you the one that shot him?
如果我什么都不知道呢？
And if I don't know any of those things?
那就没必要留着你了
Then you're of no worth to me
我会杀掉你，然后走掉
and I might as well shoot you now and leave.
约翰逊有很多名字
Johnson's had a lot of names.
我不知道到那一个是真的
Don't know one's any more real than the next.
知道会很危险的
Knowing would only be dangerous.
他当过陆军
He's ex-army.
可以肯定他得过上校军衔
Pretty sure he was a full-bird colonel.
说下去
Go on.
他们找到我就像找到你一样
They came for me, like they came for you.
让我执行一次性任务
Recruitment for a single job.
他们喜欢这样做
They like the wounded.
用起来顺手
Easier to use
用完了就可以丢掉，没人管
and then throw away when you are done.
提蒙斯，你，我
Timmons, you, me...
人一旦变成狼就很难再 听人吩咐，任人宰割
Once you've been a wolf, it's hard to be staked down like a goat.
我们两个死到临头的人 完全可以开诚布公了
This is just one dead man talking to another.
大主教怎么回事？
And the Archbishop?
你想杀人灭口又不引起怀疑么？
You want to take all suspicions away when you shoot someone,
那就等他站在总统身边再下手
wait till he's standing next to the President.
大主教想干什么？
What was he going to say?
揭露真相
The truth.
这种事情无论多么恐怖
That nothing, no matter how horrible,
要是没有政府点头是很难办到的
ever really happens without the approval of the government.
国内国外都是如此
Over there, and here.
问题不在于干了什么
The problem isn't the doing.
而在于让当权者承认…
It's the people in power having to admit
他们知情
that they knew.
阿布格莱布监狱的囚犯受到虐待
The prisoners are tortured at Abu Ghraib,
只有普通士兵受到处罚
and only the underlings go to jail.
当官的完全知情
Their bosses knew.
我们知道他们知情
We know their bosses knew.
但谁也不说
But you don't say it.
非洲到底发生了什么事？
What exactly happened in Africa?
那些村民怎么也不相信
Somehow the villagers didn't think
仅仅为了一条输油管道
that an oil pipeline
就可以让他们背井离乡
was a good enough reason to move their village
搬到一个没有圣灵保佑的地方
to a place where the spirit gods didn't exist.
喝点？
Drink?
就是说他们先劝说
So they asked them all nicely to move
如果不从就杀掉？
and when they didn't, they just killed them all?
不
No.
根本不劝
They didn't ask.
直接杀掉
They just killed them.
全部杀掉
All.
于是其他村子就不用劝了
So the next village won't need to be asked.
都会听话的搬走
They'll just go.
在一个大坑里埋了四百多具尸体
There is a mass grave with 400 bodies,
男人，女人，还有孩子…
men, women, children,
就在厄立特里亚边境十公里远的 一个输油站下面
under the oil pumping station 10 kilometers over the Eritrean border.
你应该知道
You should know.
正是你们保卫的那些 承包商杀害了他们
You covered the retreat of the contractors who did the job.
当然，本来你也不该活着回来的
Of course, you weren't supposed to survive that, either.
约翰逊受谁指使？
Who runs Johnson?
一名议员，好像是蒙大拿州的
A senator. From Montana, I think.
你不明白
You don't get it.
你根本找不到罪魁祸首
There is no head to cut off.
他们是一个利益共同体
It's a conglomerate.
如果其中有谁背叛了
If one of them betrays the principles
财富积累的原则
of the accrual of money and power,
他就会被抛弃
the others betray him.
这是人的贪婪本性所决定的
What it is
is human weakness.
是无法用枪除掉的
You can't kill that with a gun.
史瓦格
Swagger.
你必须马上离开 到处都是他们的人
You got to get out of there. They're everywhere.
我必须留住你等他们赶到
Had to keep you till they got here.
Walther P99
谎话是留不住你的
Lying wasn't going to hold you.
你马上会识破
You would have known.
瓦尔特P99自动手枪由该公司于1997推出
握把部份可依照使用者的手掌大小，有3种尺寸可供选择
顺带一提 你的女人在他们的手里
By the way, they've got your woman.
此枪的舒适性广受好评
史瓦格
Swagger.
他们离你只有二十码了 你必须马上出来
They're 20 yards and closing. You got to get out of there.
快去第二隐蔽处 明白
- Bug out. Go to hide two. - Roger that.
史瓦格，我到了第二隐蔽处
Swagger, I'm in position two.
你必须马上离开
You got to get out of there.
到处都是他们的人 嘿
- They're all over the place. - Hey!
冷静点
Calm down.
听我命令，引爆外面的铁管炸弹
Blow the pipe bombs outside on my call, okay? You got it?
我明白
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, I got it.
听好了
Listen very carefully.
我数到一 先引爆铁管炸弹
On my one, you blow the pipe bombs,
然后汽油弹
then the gas.
三，二，一
Three, two, one...
引爆汽油弹！
Hit it. Hit the napalm.
史瓦格！
Swagger!
你一定行的
You got it.
史瓦格！
Swagger!
听我的命令，躲到后面谷仓去
You got to bug out on my go behind that barn.
好的
Okay.
准备好了？ 是的
- You ready? - Yeah.
走！
Go!
快走
Come on!
俄罗斯RPD式轻机枪
RPD式轻机枪是由前苏联捷格加廖夫
于1943年设计、1946年开始批量生产的
我们得躲到树林那边去
You got to gun it to that tree line.
什么？
What?
还有五发子弹把那鸟引过来
You got five shots left. Gotta draw that bird out.
好的
Okay. Okay.
我来掩护你 好的
- On my cover, all right? - Okay.
好的！行动
All right, go!
拉高！拉高！
Pull up! Pull up!
是时候走了
Time to go!
让我看看
Let me take a look.
现在不行
Not right now.
早上好，美人
Morning, beautiful.
看到弗吉尼亚州的枪战了吗？ 长官？
- See this weird shootout in Virginia? - Sir...
弹痕累累，到处是直升机残骸 和血迹，但就是没有尸体
Shells everywhere, helicopter remnants, blood. No bodies, though, right?
他们提取了两组留在弹壳上得指纹
And they get fingerprints off the cartridge cases.
第一组毫无疑问是 鲍勃・李・史瓦格的
First set positively IDed as Bob Lee Swagger.
第二组是 FBI 特工 尼克・孟菲斯的
Second set belongs to Special Agent Nick Memphis
of the FBl.
也许搞错了
What? That's gotta be wrong.
对此我只想问一点…
Now, the only reasonable question to ask after that is,
这他妈的到底是怎么回事？
what the fuck is going on?
好枪法
Great shot!
轮到你了，丹 好枪法
- All yours, Dan! - Good shooting!
我开始觉得你不适合这份工作了
I'm beginning to think that you were the wrong man for the job.
随你怎么想好了
Think what you want.
我们显然低估了那个枪炮军士
It appears we misjudged the gunnery sergeant.
总有个神经错乱的人
There's always a confused soul
想要改变世界
that thinks that one man can make a difference.
你必须要把他干掉 才能改变他的想法
And you have to kill him to convince him otherwise.
这就是民主带来的麻烦
That's the hassle with democracy.
发射
Pull!
蒙大拿州，波兹曼
已经火烧屁股了 明白我的意思吗？
...fire under their asses, you understand me?
我要立刻拿到报告
We need those results now.
安娜你马上派人去 那个歌舞餐厅
Anna, you guys, you take the team... Anna!... to the roadhouse.
我现在不管是谁打来的
Okay, I don't care who it is right now. I don't give...
安静！孟菲斯的电话
Guys! We got Memphis on the line.
马上跟踪
Start a trace.
没问题
Got it. I'm on it.
尼克，我是霍华德 你怎么样？
Nick. Hey, it's Howard here. How are you?
事情有点复杂了 我已经拘留了史瓦格
Things have gotten a little complicated. I got Bob Lee Swagger in custody.
没错，霍华德 他确实没有死
Yeah, turns out he's not dead, Howard.
是的，我知道有那种可能
Yeah, I know. Word of that possibility had begun to reach us.
查到了
Got him.
你似乎在弗吉尼亚参加了枪战？
Were you in a gunfight in Virginia last night?
我说过了，事情变得有点复杂了
Like I said, things have gotten a little complicated.
当然，如果你要是能把他带回来 那就再好不过了
Well, obviously the best thing for you would be to bring him in, right?
不，我做不到
Oh, no. I can't do that.
为什么？
Why?
我不知道应该相信谁
It's gotten too deep. It's not clear who can be trusted.
我们可是 FBI 是的，我知道
- But we're the FBl, son. - Yeah, I know.
我会保持联系
Yeah, I'll keep in touch.
尼克， 等等！
Oh, Nick, wait...
该死的家伙！
Son of a bitch.
查到了？ 嗯
- Did we get that? - Got him.
我们出发 他们在蒙大拿州…
- Let's move. - They're on an interstate
波兹曼市郊的州际公路 快出发
- outside Bozeman, Montana. - Let's move!
我是史瓦格
This is Swagger.
我是约翰逊上校 我知道你在监听
- Colonel Johnson here. - Figured you'd be listening.
看来你走投无路了 上校？
- It appears you have nowhere to go. - Colonel?
如果你真是上校？
If it is 'Colonel'?
我是
It is.
我这有你想要的东西 我也是
- I have something you want. - Well, it seems so do I.
就在厄立特里亚边境 一个大坑里埋了四百多具尸体
Over the Eritrean border, there is a mass grave with 400 bodies.
男人，女人，还有孩子
Men, women, children.
我可以拿它跟你作交换
Tell you what, I'll give it to you and we'll call it even.
但我需要一个可以信任的中间人
I just want someone there I can trust.
可以，你的人选是谁？
I'm amenable. Who do you have in mind?
那个U2*组合里总戴副墨镜的家伙怎么样？ *爱尔兰著名乐队
How about that guy from U2 with the glasses?
他至少是纳尔逊・曼德拉*的朋友似乎值得信任 *南非首位黑人总统，诺贝尔和平奖获得者
Friend of Nelson Mandela and all. He seems trustworthy.
博诺*？你想要他们把博诺找来？ *U2乐队主唱，同时还是出色的社会活动家
Bono? You want them to get Bono?
我的朋友不同意
My colleague's questioning my choice. Okay,
我知道这太难为你了 那我就退一步
I see how that could be a tough problem. You know, last minute and all.
蒙大拿州连任六届的参议员 查尔斯・米奇恩怎么样？
How about six-term senator Charles Meachum
from Montana?
我认为这是个不错的第二选择
Seems like a pretty good second choice, don't you think?
我不这么想
I don't think so.
我先给你提供两个数字 然后我们再谈
I'm gonna provide you with two numbers, then we'll talk.
点 732，点 648
Point 732. Point 648.
你到底什么意思？
And what the hell is that?
他们是纬度和经度的后三位数字
Those are the last three digits, down to a few meters of latitude and longitude,
地点是厄立特里亚一个输油站
of an oil pipeline pumping station in Eritrea
下面埋有四百多具尸体
with 400 bodies underneath.
我们在哪见面？
Where are we meeting?
随便在哪都行
Somewhere I can see you,
但是要在离你足够远的地方
coming from a goddamn long way off.
你男朋友在哪？
Where's your boy?
好吧，我到了
Well, I'm here.
他来了
He's here.
看啊
Look, look, look.
那是你男友，宝贝
There's your boy. There's your boy, baby.
快看，快看
Come on, come on. Look, look. Look up.
雷明登700
完事了
Okay.
我好像断了一条肋骨
I think I broke a rib!
别动
Don't move!
还有其他狙击手吗？
Is there anybody else?
没了
No.
如果我被打中，她也不会活着
He head-shoots me, spasm kills her!
不许开枪
You got no shot!
不许开枪，史瓦格你听到了没有？
No shot, Swagger! You hear that, Swagger?
不许开枪
You got no shot!
你想怎么样？
What are you gonna do? Come on!
你完蛋了，伙计
It's over for you, buddy!
不许开枪，干他
No shot! Okay, fuck him.
不赖嘛！
Not bad!
够水平，好枪法，有两下子
Pretty good! He went for the shot.
见鬼
Christ.
你有什么事？
How can we help you?
一位住客给我一百美元
Guest at the motel last night gave me $100
让我下午三点把这个送来
to bring this by here at 3:00 p. m.
寄信人：尼克・孟菲斯
行动！
Let's move!
你没事吧？
You all right?
没事
Yeah.
搜一下
Search him.
我没带武器
I don't carry a weapon,
今天例外
ordinarily.
我有本州的持枪许可证
I'm licensed to carry that in this state.
伯莱塔M92FS INOX
要飞行员下来
Pull the pilot.
属于M9系列手枪，除底把外
快把武器放下！
Put your weapon down! Put it down!
大部分金属零件都是不锈钢
把武器放下！
Put your gun down!
冷静，冷静
Easy. Easy.
莎拉
Sarah.
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
好了，把枪给我
It's okay. Give me the gun.
你没事吧？
You okay?
举起手来，把手举起来
Put them up. Keep them up.
好枪法，军士
Nice shooting, Gunnie.
你得到了你想要的东西
Yeah, you got what you came for.
现在给我我想要的
I think it's time you owe us your side of the bargain.
是吗？
You do, huh?
是的，当然是的
Yes, I do, son. I certainly do.
我们姑且把这事看成
Why don't we think about all this that has gone on
一个好的开始
just as a preamble?
你有什么打算？
You got any plans after this?
你的枪法很准 我很乐意为你提供一份工作
You have a rather unique skill set. I'd be interested in offering you a job.
为你工作？
Work? For you?
实际上没有你想的那么糟 我的目的不管怎样都会实现
It's not really as bad as it seems. It's all gonna be done in any case.
站在我这边你可以 得到一份可观的薪水
You might as well be on the side that gets you well paid for your efforts.
你是哪一边的？
And what side are you on?
其实无所谓哪一边 无所谓逊尼派还是什叶派
There are no sides. There's no Sunnis and Shiites.
没有民主党也没有共和党
There's no Democrats and Republicans.
有的只是穷人和富人
There's only haves and have-nots.
那我能为你干什么呢？参议员
What exactly does working for you entail, Senator?
强奸妇女？杀戮儿童？ 你这变态
Raping and murdering innocent women and children, you sick fuck?
为了一条输油管线
You sanctioned the mass murder of an entire village
你居然能杀掉整个村的村民
so a pipeline could go through.
就一个村的！
One village!
但这给整个地区带来了安宁
And it brought stability to the region.
从此以后他们不会因为
Which means that no one chops off their arms
祖上属于不同的部落而进行仇杀
because their grandmother's grandfather
belonged to a different tribe.
他们喜欢我们，年轻人
They like us down there, boy.
在我们国家
This is a country
就连国防部长…
where the Secretary of Defense
都能到电视上…
can go on TV
对公众发表这样的演说词
and tell the American public,
“这是为了自由不是为了石油”
oh, that 'This is about freedom! It's not about oil!'
没有人会质疑他
And nobody questions him,
因为没有人想揭穿他那十足的谎言
because they don't want to hear the answer
because it's a lie!
进我的权力核心工作 没那么容易，军士
There's only so many places at the table, Gunnie.
你是想进来呢？
Now are you on the inside,
还是想留在外面？
or are you on the out?
是 FBI！
It's the FBl!
没关系，拿着
It's gonna be okay. Hold this.
如果其中有谁背叛了 财富积累的原则…
If one of them betrays the principles of the accrual...
你打错算盘了，参议员
I don't think so, Senator.
你要干什么？ 救你我的命
- What are you doing? - Saving our lives.
它能证明你是无辜的！ 这里没有无辜的人
- That proved you were innocent! - Nobody out here is innocent!
这东西就像放射性物质 接触的人必死无疑
This stuffs plutonium. Nobody can handle it without dying.
一旦交给当局 它就会跟我们一起消失
You hand it over to the authorities, it's just gonna disappear, along with us!
你不想被埋在郊外吧 我也不想被抓
Unless you want to get buried in the hills outside Terlingua.
我不玩了，老鬼
I'm out, old man!
我是个粗人，我习惯了 在山顶过艰苦的日子
I'm just a peckerwood who lives in the hills with too many guns.
你满意了吗？
You happy?
你们去哪？
Where do you think you're going?
回华盛顿
Washington!
你想从背后杀死 一位在任的参议员？
You going to shoot a sitting U.S. senator in the back?
老实说，我很想
Lord knows I want to.
你不会这样做的
I didn't think so.
让他走
Let him go.
他们拿到了你的步枪
They've got your rifle.
他们一开始就拿到了你的步枪
From the beginning, they've always had your rifle.
就在谋杀的现场
Recovered at the site.
无论你怎样辩解
You can talk as much as you want, but in the end,
最终还是会被判处注射死刑* *向犯人体内注射毒药的一种死刑
you're going to die by lethal injection,
而我？该干嘛还是干嘛
and I'm going to go back to what I was doing.
我赢了
I won.
你输了
You lost.
听天由命吧，孩子
Get used to the idea, son.
我不是你的孩子
I'm not your son.
放下武器 ！放下武器！ 别动
- Drop your weapons! Put it down now! - Don't move!
我是尼克・孟菲斯探员 我是 FBI，别开枪！
Special Agent Nick Memphis, FBl! Don't shoot!
趴下！ 趴在地上
- Down, now! - On the ground!
我说趴下！
I said get down!
司法部，华盛顿特区
可以给我解开吗？ 可以
- Could I free my hands, please? - It's okay.
谢谢
Thank you, sir.
谢谢把她带来
Thanks for bringing her.
我对这一切很抱歉
Hey. I'm sorry about everything.
不怪你，事情就是这个样子的
It's not your fault. It is what it is.
这位是司法部长罗瑟
This is Attorney General Russert.
联邦调查局局长布兰特 长官
- Director Brandt. - Sir.
米奇恩议员今天不能到场
Senator Meachum couldn't be with us today.
没有他我们一样可以开会
I'm sure we can manage without him.
Cheytac Intervention M200
史瓦格军士 这次会议是你要求的
Sergeant Swagger, you asked for this meeting.
尽管我不情愿 但看在 FBI 的面子上我还是同意了
Against my better judgment, I've agreed to it as a favor to the FBl.
这里有我什么事？
What the hell am I doing here?
我和本案毫无牵连，我是清白的
You've got nothing on me. I'm covered.
你可以去问参谋长联席会议* *美国军事体系中军令系统的最高指挥机构，负责拟制、组织实施战略计划等
Call the Joint Chief.
没必要，上校
That won't be necessary, Colonel,
我至少接到了十几个电话
as I have already received no less than a dozen calls
高官们都要求我能够放你一马
from highly-ranked and powerfully-placed individuals
telling me to let you go.
但令人欣喜的是，我们宪法规定的权力制衡*体制 *行政、立法、司法三权分立，每一分支都对另两个分支具有制约作用，从而形成权力平衡
But the joy of checks and balances in our government is that I can,
以法律的名义叫他们滚蛋
and am, indeed, required by law,
to tell them to fuck off.
这次会议是为了查明真相
This is about evidence and finding out the truth,
所以你最好坐着别乱开口
so you sit there and be quiet.
军士，给你五分钟的时间
Sergeant, you've got five minutes.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是我的步枪
This is my weapon.
毫无疑问，我不否认
No question about it, don't deny it.
你们很快就在现场找到了它
You recovered it at the scene moments after the assassination.
没异议
We agree?
此后一直由 FBI 保管
It's been in the FBl's possession ever since,
保证没有人动过？
hasn't been tampered with in any way?
没有，绝对没有
No. Absolutely not.
你用它射击过吗？ 没必要
- You fire the weapon? - There was no point.
子弹已经损毁得无法辨认了
The slug was mangled beyond recognition.
但是经过材质鉴定完全吻合
It was, however, an exact metallurgical match.
没错，这绝对是我的子弹
Right. Definitely my bullets.
这绝对是我的步枪
Definitely my gun.
孟菲斯，你相信是我开的枪吗？
Special Agent Memphis, you believe I shot that Archbishop?
不，我不相信
Nope. No, I don't.
你有什么证据吗？ 没有
- Have any proof of this fact? - No.
你相信我吗？ 是的
- Trust me? - Yep.
真的相信？
Really trust me?
真的
Yeah.
用性命担保
With your life?
是的 那好
- Yep. - Good.
你想干什么？ 把枪放下
- What the hell are you doing? - Put that weapon down now!
如果这么近距离射击 枪口要再低一些
If you're zeroed for 600, you ought to aim a little lower.
这么近，没有必要
Ain't gonna make a difference this close.
关键要看我是不是疯了
Only thing that's gonna make a difference
is whether I'm crazy or not.
我经常花一整天摆弄…
I could keep doing this all day,
家里所有的武器
with every weapon in my house.
但在我出门的时候，我总是把所有的撞针*都拆掉 *用以撞击底火发射子弹的枪械物件
I swapped all the firing pins before I left the house. I always do.
很难察觉，除非用千分尺来测量
Looks right, need a micrometer to tell.
但枪绝对打不出子弹
But the gun don't shoot.
大主教身上的子弹 的确出自我的步枪
That bullet you got out of that bishop was fired from my weapon,
那是一周前打铁罐用的
but a week before, at a can of stew.
我发过誓要忠于祖国 抵抗国内外敌人侵害
I did take an oath to defend this country from all enemies, foreign and domestic.
但没想到有人要陷害我
I just didn't figure I'd end up quite this involved.
当尘埃落定之后
But at the end of the day, when all the dust settles,
你不要以为真相可以 轻易掩盖，混蛋
you can't hide from the truth, you son of a bitch.
随你的便
Whatever.
谁会相信？
Who gives a shit?
你表演得不错
Nice presentation.
可跟我毫无关系
But none of it sticks to me.
先生们，会议结束了
Gentlemen, this meeting is over.
结束了
Done.
后会有期
I'll be seeing you.
他说得对，没有证据说明他犯了罪
He's right. There's nothing to prove he did anything.
在国内没有
Yeah, in this country.
先生，你应该看看这个
Sir, you should take a look at these.
这些照片来自于一份绝密文件 能证明在非洲的一个村子里
These images are from a classified file showing a village of people in Africa
全部村民被上校和他的同伙杀掉
that were exterminated by the colonel and his associates.
上帝啊
My God.
请不要忘记
Look around you.
这里不是非洲之角
This isn't the Horn of Africa.
那只是些传闻
That's all hearsay.
这里是自由之地，勇敢者的家园
This is the land of the free and the home of the brave.
我有离开的自由
And I'm free to go.
上校，你的道德观完全变态了
Colonel, your moral compass is so fucked up,
我怀疑你是否还能 面不改色心不跳地回到停车场
I'll be shocked if you manage to find your way back to the parking lot.
不管我对这些事情有怎样的看法
Regardless of how I feel about this,
它都是发生在别的国家
these events occurred in another country,
不是我国境内
outside of our laws.
原来是这样？就没有别的办法吗？
So that's it? That's the best you can do?
这里不是国际法庭，军士
This isn't the World Court, Sergeant.
我无权扣留上校
And I don't have the jurisdiction to detain the colonel
不管他是否真的在国外 犯下了那些罪行
for crimes he may or may not have committed on another continent.
先生，我恳请你重新考虑一下 没什么可考虑的
- Sir, I urge you to reconsider... - There's nothing to reconsider, son.
我赢了
I win.
而你这次
You lose.
又输了
Again.
简直太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
说实话我比你更不喜欢这个结果
For the record, I don't like the way this turned out any more than you do.
但这就是我们生活的世界
But this is the world we live in.
法律也不是万能的
And justice does not always prevail.
这不是早期的西部
It's not the Wild West,
不能用枪解决所有问题
where you can clean up the streets with a gun.
尽管有时你必须那样做
Even though sometimes that's exactly what's needed.
鲍勃・李・史瓦格，你自由了
Bob Lee Swagger, you're free to go.
给他打开脚镣
Unshackle the sergeant.
我们打出了一记重拳，参议员
I'd say that's quite a shot, Senator.
正中目标
In the face.
有句话说得好
You heard that expression,
“打掉牙齿只能往肚里吞”
'You didn't know whether to shit or go blind'?
H&K G36KE
你真该看看司法部长脸上的表情
You should've seen the look on the Attorney General's face.
他是不是又谈 “权力制衡”的老调了？
Did he give his checks-and-balances speech?
“这是为了举证和查明真相”
'This is about evidence and the truth!'
你应该直接了当地对他说
And then you just said to him,
“见你的鬼”
'Fuck you!'
“一边呆着去，部长先生”
'Hold my cigar, Mr. A.G.'
见你的鬼
'Fuck you!
我说的话就是真相
'The truth is what I say it is!'
你明天一早就离开美国
You know, you got to be out of the country in the morning.
去厄瓜多尔
You're going to Ecuador.
我们和当地人弄出了点麻烦
Well, we're having some problems with the locals.
我们的人已经做好准备把事情摆平
We have our personnel on the ground ready to neutralize the problem, but...
不过点名要你帮忙
Well, they've requested you.
小事一桩
It's solvable.
他们点名要你
They requested you...
史瓦格
Swagger.
把灯关掉
Turn off the lights!
去开车！
Get my car.
快想办法
Do something.
Do something!
他在哪？
Where is he?
M1911系列
在地板下面
He's under the floor!
柯尔特 M1911 式点45口径自动手枪
是世界上最著名的手枪之一
是世界上装备时间最长，装备量最大的手枪
你没必要杀我
You don't need to kill me.
你没必要杀我，是他们干的！
You don't need to kill me. It was them.
他们干的！
It was them.
等等！请等一下！
God damn it! Just wait a minute!
冷静一下
Hold it just a minute. Hold it.
你是不是疯了？ 是不是真的发疯了？
Are you out of your mind? Are you out of your damn mind?
我是美国的现任参议员
I am a United States senator!
那更该死
Exactly.
-= 谢谢观看 =-